

# Senior Full-Stack Web Engineer

### Jorge Albaladejo Pomares

Renens, Vaud, Switzerland Age: 38 (Sept. 1981) Spanish nationality / Swiss permit C Spanish / English / French
+41 79 725 97 37
hello@jorgealbaladejo.com
LinkedIn / UpWork / Arc / Portfolio

#### Resume

With over 12 years of professional experience and a MSc. ICT Software Engineering, my career goal is to help build complex and multidisciplinary doud applications.

My motto is: quality by design. I build production apps that can serve thousands of monthly users with virtually zero bugs (0.05% of the visits) and handle millions of new monthly records in a timely manner (under 200ms response time).

All of my previous clients and employers are highly satisfied with my work and have ranked me as a **top rated freelancer** – you can check my <u>UpWork</u> and <u>LinkedIn</u> profiles for additional references. I am also part of the <u>Arc</u>'s **vetted developer** network.

**Profile**: back-end architecture, database E/R design, requirements analysis, front-end development, user interface design, prototyping, REST API design, QA engineering, Linux server administration, legacy software debugging and maintenance.

**Technical Skills**: PHP 7, Laravel 5, MySQL, Javascript (ES8), Vue.js, React, AngularJS, Ember.js, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Material UI, CSS3, SASS, HTML5, Git, NPM, Composer, Jenkins, Bitbucket Pipelines, Docker, PHPUnit, Behat, Cypress, Amazon Web Services, Codelgniter, Zend Framework, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Node.js, MongoDB, Jira, Kanban, SCRUM, TDD & BDD, Bugsnag.

**Soft Skills**: technical coordination in multi-cultural distributed teams spanning across multiple time zones; dynamic and proactive, "getting things done" attitude; detail-oriented and user-centered philosophy.

## Professional Experience

#### 2017 – Present: Freelance Senior Full-Stack Engineer (Remote)

- Working for agencies, NGOs and retail clients in Europe, USA, Canada and Australia to develop and maintain custom web
  software applications, including e-catalogs, learning management systems, content management systems, health care portals,
  e-commerce platforms, travel planners and decision support systems for youths in college.
- My services cover either integrating my clients' engineering teams as a consultant, either conducting the full software life cycle management from design to implementation, test, deployment and maintenance.

#### 2015 – 2016: Senior Full-Stack Web Engineer (Remote)

- <u>Cause Labs</u> is a web agency specialized in digital strategy, consultancy and software solutions for NGOs.
- My duties ranged from sever maintenance on AWS to back-end architecture, REST API implementation and front-end development and occasional help with UI / UX design.
- Main developer for several projects involving new architectures and maintaining legacy code, such as:
  - MoneyThink: design and development of a REST API compliant with the <u>HAL</u> specification.
  - OppNet: development of a full course management system, with an admin CMS and role-based user workflows.

#### 2014: Front-End Software Engineer

- <u>BugBuster SA</u> is a startup from EPFL founded in 2010. They build a SaaS cloud application for automated web testing.
- I improved the user experience on the Front-End interface and redesigned it according to Visual Management and Usability principles, to provide an easier navigation and a better visibility on the information.

#### 2011 – 2012: Front-End Dojo Engineer

- Genius Inside SA is based in Lausanne and provides a SaaS solution for project portfolio management.
- I helped improving the front-end architecture of the <u>Genius Project</u> project portfolio management suite by defining coding best
  practices, redesigning the underlying software architecture of a live app serving hundreds of clients, designing new user
  interfaces, forms and widgets and implementing new modules, all in a **SCRUM** environment and coordinating with a remote
  team in Montreal.

#### 2009 – 2010: Back-End Web Developer

- <u>Sensorscope Sàrl</u> is a startup from EPFL, specialized in network wireless sensors for weather monitoring.
- I built <u>Climaps</u> a meteorological monitoring application based on LAMP. My duties included: requirements analysis; database E/R design and optimization to handle millions on new monthly records; application development; coordination with student and support engineers to build and integrate modules and sub-projects; and server maintenance and scripting.

#### 2007 - 2008: QA Team Lead

- <u>Trymedia Systems</u>, now <u>GameHouse</u>, provided a DRM solution for video games called ActiveMARK.
- My main responsibilities included leading the QA team, optimizing QA processes, designing test cases, writing internal software tools, coordinating with remote teams and helping the team increase weekly productivity by 400% in under two years.

#### 2001 – 2006: Freelance web developer and entrepreneur.

• I co-founded a web development <u>studio</u>, where I helped many clients achieve their goals by designing and implementing integral web solutions.

#### Education

#### Master of Sciences in Information & Communication Technologies, Minor in Software Engineering

- 2012 2014: HES-SO, Lausanne, Switzerland.
- Main courses: Project Management, Data Management & Software Architecture. Grade: 5.5 / 6.
- Thesis: "A Multi-Project Management Solution for Micro-Companies" [Comodoro]. Grade: 5.5 / 6.

#### Bachelor of Engineering in Telecommunications, Minor in Electronic Systems

- 2004 2010: Miguel Hernández University (UMH), Elche, Spain
- Degree obtained in a part-time basis to complement my professional experience. Grade: 7.1 / 10.
- Thesis: "Web Information System for the Visualization and Control of Weather Stations for Natural Risk Prevention and Monitoring Environmental Parameters" [Climaps]. Grade: 10/10.

#### Additional Training, Courses & Certifications

- 2015: <u>Professional Scrum Developer I.</u>
- 2012: Course on SaaS development with Ruby on Rails ~Coursera.org (30h)
- 2011: <u>CIW JavaScript Specialist</u> + <u>CIW Database Design Specialist</u>
- 2011: <u>CIW Web Foundations Associate Certificate</u>
- 2009: Course on Management and Leadership ~Trymedia Systems (60h)
- 2005: Course on Administration of Linux Servers ~UMH, Elche, Spain (25h)